Erastus Mwangi Njoroge

Cellphone no: +254 702 120 703 Email: eramwangiz@gmail.com

Bio Data

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Married

ID NO:29325239
Nationality: Kenyan

Personal Profile

I am a Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3+ years of tech-related experience. I am also well versed with the dynamics of IT and strive to give a prompt solution.

Education	
May 2021 – Nov 2021	Software Development
	Attained: PASS
	Moringa School
2012 - 2016	Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science
	Attained: Second Class, Upper Division
	Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology
	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education
2008 – 2011	Attained: Mean Grade B (Plain)
	Mukerenju Secondary School

Skills

- Debugging
- API design knowledge
- Hardware and software installation
- Django Specialist
- Solutions deployment
- Proficient in Python, Flask, Django, CSS, JS, Angular, among other web development languages.
- Fast Learner
- Proficient in Statistical data analysis using MS EXCEL, SPSS and R-studio

Work Experience

November 2020 to May 2021 EPIC GIFTS AND DESIGNS

Position: ICT Support

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining and troubleshooting all network and computer related issues
- Enhance office IT system through appropriate upgrades and advise Operations Unit on changes or improvements required
- Followed diagrams and written instructions to repair faults or when setting up systems
- Help install and support of ICT hardware and software
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- Worked with customers to understand needs and provide excellent service.
- Received and processed stock into inventory management system.

March 2017 to November 2020 AFRINTOM LTD

Position: ICT Officer **Responsibilities:**

- Used Microsoft Word, Google Docs and SharePoint to store and share created documents.
- Conducted extensive internet research to provide facts and statistics for articles and blogs.
- Used Figma to execute web and graphic design as well as participating in web development services.
- Performed secondary data collection and analysis using MS EXCEL, SPSS and R-studio.
- Strengthened content by thoroughly editing and proofreading content 2 times prior to submission.
- Completed thorough research into assigned topics.
- Evaluated project requirements and content standards for each project to produce copy in line with creative structure.
- Formatted articles, blogs and webpages with HTML, photos and infographics.
- Composed original written material for various types of publications and submitted for approval by supervisor, editor or publisher.
- Completed accurate and polished formatting in line with publishing standards prior to submission.

Sept 2016 to Oct 2016 Karugia Secondary School

Position: Mathematics Teacher

Responsibilities:

- Diversified teaching techniques and learning tools help students with differing ability levels and varied learning modalities.
- Assessed submitted class assignments, determined grades and reviewed work with struggling students to boost success chance.

- Utilized multimedia strategies and technology to convey information in fresh and interesting ways.
- Administered assessments and standardized tests to evaluate student progress.
- Kept classroom environments consistent and focused on learning by establishing and enforcing clear objectives.
- Supplemented textbook material with approved third-party examples and resources for clarity on difficult topics.

May - Aug 2013

Smartedge EA LTD

Position: ICT Attaché

Responsibilities:

- ICT sales and support.
- LAN cabling.
- Network configuration.
- Hardware and software installation on Ms Window platform.
- Web applications.
- Responding to other duties allocated by the manager.

May - Sept 2012

Muthurumbi Secondary school

Position: Mathematics Teacher

Responsibilities:

- Initiated communication with students to address learning concerns and offer additional guidance for independent study.
- Helped students make good decisions about course choices for educational and vocational goals.
- Addressed systematic issues with math curriculum by collaborating with colleagues.
- Held regular office hours to assist students struggling with materials.
- Provided meaningful math instruction to improve math skills of children.
- Prepared and implemented lesson plans covering required course topics.
- Developed and distributed study guides to reinforce lecture details and help students with test preparation.
- Implemented peer tutoring system to enhance comprehensive understanding of math techniques and increase student test scores.
- Proctored exams for students to promote educational growth.

Additional Information

Hobbies and Interests

- Designing contents using different software
- Filling Sudoku
- Exploring news about technological inventions and innovations.
- Studying and researching different programming languages

Referees

Mr. John Ngugi

Managing Director, Epic Gifts and Designs

Email: johnngugi0@gmail.com Phone: +254 710 902 720

Dr. Geoffrey Gitau

Managing Director, Smart Edge East Africa Limited

Email: gitaugk@gmail.com
Phone: +254 721 319 897

Mr. Justus Onyancha

Technical Mentor, Moringa School

Email: <u>Justus.onyancha@moringaschool.com</u>

Phone: +254 714 244 366